

About

Hands-on, dedicated professional with over 10 years of experience in Hospitality IT management. Possess strong knowledge of the software development and IT product design lifecycle. My objective to secure challenges and responsibilities in an organization where is a scope of contributing and updating my knowledge and skill in order to develop myself and organization

IT Skills

Operating Systems:

Windows XP, Window Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10

Server Side Technologies:

2000, 2003, 2008r2, 2012r2 server.

Security (Anti-Virus):

Symantec Endpoint 12.1 (Server), Seqrite Endpoint Security 17.0 Server) Quick-Heal endpoint security 6.0(Server)

Backup Software:

Symantec Backup Exec 12.5, sql Server Backup

VIPIN KUMAR

Vill- Chandnamau, Post- Arahariyamau Dist- Kanpur Rural, Uttar Pradesh - 209312

Mobile: 91 99560 28451

E-mail: sachanvipin4@gmail.com

Skype: vipin.sachan1

Professional Experience – 11 years and 8 months

Aurika Coorg (Lemon Tree Hotels) Pre-opening

Asst. IT Manager (HOD), From Jan 2021 to till now

| 5 Star Luxury Hotels | 55 Rooms | 3 Room category | 2 Banquets |

ITC Fortune JPS Grand Rajkot.

Asst. IT Manager (HOD), From Oct 2019 to till Dec 2020 | 5 Star Hotel | 77 Rooms | 3 Room category | 2 Banquets |

The Park Prime Ranchi.

IT Manager From May 2017 to Sep 2019.

| 4 Star Hotel | 63 Rooms | 3 Room Category | 2 Banquets |

Club O7/Grand O7 Ahmedabad

IT Manager (Pre-opening), From June 2016 to April 2017
| 5 Star Residential Club | 125 Rooms | 4 Room Category | Club management | 2
Banquets |

Golden Tulip, Ranchi.

IT Manager (Pre-opening), From Sep 2011 to May 2016 | 4 Star Hotel | 62 Rooms | 3 Room Category | 2 Banquets |

The Landmark Hotel, Kanpur.

Sr. System Executive, From July 2010 to Aug 2011 | 5 Star Hotel | 115 Rooms | 3 Room Category | 4 Banquets |

Ankish Automation (P) Ltd, Kanpur.

IT Support Engineer, From Aug 2009 to July 2010 | IBM and HP Authorized Service partner |

Area of Expertise and Job Responsibilities

Technical Application

- A) IT application strategy planning & analysis for establish or set up new business to achieve planned targets.
- B) Possess knowledge about IDS Next 4.1, 6.1, 6.5, Opera Property Management System, Micros POS, PRISMHR, Boss, Tally, Matrix and GDS for reservation booking.
- C) Designing, launching & implementing IT activities based on the requirements of the business.
- D) Co-ordination with all functional departments for successful IT implementation.
- E) Network and hardware maintenance, troubleshooting and diagnosis.
- F) Attending user's problem, bug fixing and housekeeping.
- G) System and database administration.
- H) Network design and implementation.
- I) Fire-wall. Antivirus, disaster and back-up management.
- J) Lead IT department and solving end user's problems.

Certification Course

Microsoft Certified Professional Microsoft (MCP ID#6214841) From 2009 to 2011

From 2009 to 2011 Modules Covered in 2008

Hardware Networking Diploma

NET centric Computer Networking Learning Centre, Kanpur. From 2007 to 2009

O' LEVEL Diploma in computer Application

NICE Angle Computer Centre, Kanpur. From 2005 to 2007

Language(s)

English – Read - Fluently English – Write -Fluently English – Speak -Fluently Hindi – Read – Fluently Hindi – Write – Fluently Hindi – Speak – Fluently

Personal Information:

Father's Name: Gauri

Shankar

Date of Birth: Aug 10th

1987

Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Single

Gender: Male

System administration skill

- A) Installing windows server 2003, 2008R2, 2012R2 and basic configuration.
- B) Network architecture, protocol, share and permission.
- C) IP addressing and TCP/IP services and application.
- D) Installing network and troubleshooting
- E) Client/Server system & remote connectivity
- F) Network Monitoring, Backup & Restore
- G) Auditing & terminal services
- H) (AD DC) Active Directory Domain Services, GPO (Group Policy) working with local user account & groups / Domain account & Domain groups
- I) Setup, Installation, Managing and Maintaining Backup of Sql Server, RAID.
- J) Manage & Maintenance of Door Lock system with RF Decoder interface with specific software supplied by the company
- K) Rectify Security Surveillance System CCTV- (Analog, IP Cameras)

Client Servicing

- A) Consistent Focus on devising and putting in place systems and procedures revolving around the need of the client/customer
- B) Ensuring customer satisfaction by achieving delivery of service quality norms.
- C) Implementing world-class service strategies. Interaction with guests to troubleshoot on complaints.
- D) Strategizing policies & procedures in the operating systems to achieve greater customer delight.
- E) Reviewing & interpreting the market trends/ client feedback to attune the business strategies as per the customer requirements & expectations.
- F) Conference AV system Set up, Projection, Sound System
- G) Cisco Switches, WLC, ADSL Router, Cisco Access Point and Modem etc.

Educational Qualification

Master's in Business Administration Information Technology & HR

Sikkim Manipal University – RANCHI, From 2013 to 2015.

Bachelor of Arts

Hindi Literature and Sociology

Chhatrapati Shahu Ji Maharaj University – Kanpur, From 2009 to 2012

Declaration

Consider myself familiar with I T Infrastructure Aspects. I am also confident of my ability to work in a team. I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Signature Date & Place